Abigayle L. Reeves

Raleigh, NC 27606 | (C) 252-675-8945 | 16areeves@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Analytical Scientist with 4+ years' experience who thrives in fast-paced environments. Enjoys working as part of a team and independently to achieve goals while learning new techniques.

Skills

Advanced Excel 2018-2022, VBA Programming, Python Programming 3.10, Jupyter Notebook, PostGreSQL, NoSQL, Sqlite, pgAdmin 4 version 6.8, Web Scraping using Jupyter Notebook, API Calls, Microsoft Office 2022, Command Line Executions, Creating SSH Keys, GitHub and Markdown, Aseptic Testing, Sterile Techniques, LIMS, LIFT, SAP, and Documentum Experience, Analytical Lab Skills (FTIR, GC, HPLC, UV/Vis, Karl Fischer and ICP-OES), Software (TotalChrom, Empower 3 feature release 2, 3 and 4), Hardware (PerkinElmer, Clarus 400, Agilent, Ametek / Spectro, Cosa, Genesis), cGMP and cGLP Guidelines, CPR/AED/Narcan Certified, Veeva QMS System, ComplianceWire LMS System, MyLearning LMS, Lab Auditing

Work History

• Assistant Scientist - QC Micro - GlaxoSmithKline Permanent Employee

40 hours per week: August 2021 - current

Responsibilities:

- 1. Microbiology testing in support of company production:
 - a. Environmental monitoring in support of Multi-Dose Inhalers (MDI), Multi-Dose Pulmonary Inhaler (MDPI), and tablet production.
 - b. Environmental monitoring air sampling via SAS air sampler, non-viable testing via climet sampler, and swab testing. Testing performed under aseptic gowning conditions.
 - c. Aseptic gowning into isolator areas where production and packaging takes place.
 - d. Contemporaneously enters data into the SAP system to update sample status, run reports, and report testing results.
 - e. Aseptic product testing of MDPI medications using bioburden and federal regulated procedures inside BioSafety Cabinets.
 - f. Enters data into LIFT, a LIMS interface, for analysis, trending and visualizations.
- 2. General Lab Support
 - a. Ensures the lab supplies are stocked and easily accessible for testing along with helping other analysts as needed.
 - b. Supports team members with sterile product testing and other lab responsibilities.
 - c. General lab cleaning and organizing.
 - d. Ensures the lab is in a 5S state and inspection ready. Routinely audits the areas in the lab to keep the area inspection ready.
- Bench Scientist Chemist 2 (contracted to GlaxoSmithKline through ProClinical Staffing)

40 hours per week: May 2020 - August 2021

Responsibilities:

1. Analytical testing in support of MDI Manufacturing (Year 1):

- a. Analyzed multi-dose inhalers for total drug content by HPLC using Empower 3 FR2 and Empower 3 FR4. Isocratic techniques including VWD and FLD analysis in support of product release.
- b. Analyzed inhalers for foreign particulate matter by counting particles using a MIDAS particle counter. Testing performed under aseptic conditions.
- c. Analyzed inhalers for moisture content using a Karl-Fischer Moisture Meter. Routinely cleaned Karl-Fischer moisture meter to ensure appropriate system conditions.
- d. Analyzed inhalers for specific drugs using an FTIR in support of product release testing.
- e. Analyzed inhalers for spray pattern and shot-weight to ensure device functionality in support of product release and stability testing.
- f. Contemporaneous entry of all data into Sapphire/LIFT software.
- g. Support of multi-dose inhalers on stability and product release value streams.
- 2. General Lab Support
 - a. HPLC experience with Agilent 1100/1200/1260 Series.
 - b. General Laboratory Cleaning and Organizing.
 - c. Labeled vials for various team members in support of on-going testing. Helped team members as needed to meet daily standard work.
- 3. Microbiology testing in support of company production (April 2021 August 2021):
 - a. Environmental monitoring in support of Multi-Dose Inhalers (MDI), Multi-Dose Pulmonary Inhaler (MDPI), and tablet production.
 - b. Environmental monitoring air sampling via SAS air sampler, non-viable testing via climet sampler, and swab testing. Testing performed under aseptic gowning conditions.
 - c. Aseptic gowning into isolator areas where production and packaging takes place.
 - d. Ensures the lab supplies are stocked and easily accessible for testing along with helping other analysts as needed.
 - e. Contemporaneously enters data into the SAP system to update sample status, run reports, and report testing results.
- Associate Analytical Scientist (contracted to Aerie Pharmaceuticals through Frankel Staffing Agency)

40+ hours per week: May 2019-May 2020

Responsibilities:

- 1. Analytical testing in support of Implant Manufacturing:
 - a. Analyzed extended-release implants for content, purity, and in vitro release rate by HPLC. Techniques included VWD, DAD, SEC-RID, and GC.
 - b. Support of extended-release implants on stability and development.
 - c. Helped create and implement spreadsheets for various projects to track formulations and standard area count to support analytical testing.
- 2. General Lab Support
 - a. HPLC Preventative Maintenance, Troubleshooting and Repair for Agilent 1100/1260 Series
 - b. Waste Removal and General Laboratory Cleaning
 - c. Laboratory Supply Management and Ordering
 - d. cGMP trained in Aerie Manufacturing Group
- QC Micro Technician (Fresenius Kabi contracted by Kelly Services)

40+ hours per week: July 2018 – April 2019

Responsibilities:

1. Microbiology testing in support of Manufacturing:

- a. Analyzed and collected water samples using aseptic techniques. Techniques included Total Organic Carbon (TOC) and Conductivity Analysis via Anatel, Bacterial Endotoxin Testing (BET) and Bioburden Analysis.
- b. Environmental Monitoring via non-viable and viable air samplers along with contact surface testing. cGMP Gowning in ISO 5 and 7 Classified Rooms to support testing.

2. General Lab Support

- a. Analyzed samples from environmental monitoring testing and recorded results contemporaneously to controlled documents.
- b. Inventory management.
- c. General Laboratory Cleaning.
- d. Use of documentum and RAP 2.0 to access-controlled SOPs.

• Medicap Pharmacy Internship

Worked over 100 hours: June 30, 2017 - July 21, 2017

Responsibilities:

- 1. Worked as a Pharmacy Technician for a graduation requirement at Barton College.
 - a. Filled prescriptions for incoming patients using a pill counter and a PRADA instrument.
 - b. Answered incoming calls and checked patients out at the front desk.
 - c. Ordered over the counter and prescription drugs for pharmacy supply management.
 - d. Maintained pharmacy appearance by general cleaning of the store.

• Peer Tutor at Barton College

Worked 9 hours per month for the Fall 2016 semester

Responsibilities-

1. Helped multiple students with homework and studying in Math, Chemistry, and Physics.

• Teacher Assistant at Kiddie Kollege of New Bern

Worked 30+ hours per week: June 26, 2015 - August 4, 2015

Responsibilities-

- 1. Supported a teacher with a room full of children.
 - a. Ensured children and the classroom adhered to the daily schedule.
 - b. Created activities and inspired reading amongst the group.
 - c. General household cleaning to upkeep a safe environment.

Education

UNC Chapel Hill Bootcamp -

Remote

Current Grade: A

Currently Attending: Data Analytics Bootcamp Certificate Program: February 23 - August 10th, 2022

GitHub Link

Finished Learning Modules:

- 1. Advanced Excel including:
 - a. Statistical Modeling, Forecasting, Prediction, and Pivot tables
 - b. VBA Programming and Scripting
- 2. Python 3.10 Programming including:
 - a. Jupyter Notebook, API calls, JSON, NumPy, Pandas, MatPlotLib, and Beautiful Soup
 - b. Using the Command line and Anaconda Prompt to execute code
 - c. Creation of SSH Key using the Command line
 - d. GitHub Repository Creation and Maintenance
- 3. SQL and NoSQL Programming including:
 - a. Postgres / pgAdmin 4
 - b. MongoDB

Modules Left to Learn:

- 1. Visualization and Programming Tools:
 - a. HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Leaflet, Tableau, Hadoop, and Machine Learning

Barton College -

Wilson County, NC

GPA- 3.56

Graduated with Honors, May 2018

Bachelor of Science in Chemistry

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics

Craven Community College –

Craven County, NC

GPA- 3.584 unweighted

Graduated with Honors, May 2015

Associates in Arts Associates in Arts, Psychology

Associates in Science Associates in Arts, Social Work

Associates in Arts, Sociology Associates in General Education

Accomplishments

'Marriage of Chemistry and Art' research project analyzing metals using ICP-OES

Presented at Campbell University SNCURCS 2017

Presented at Barton College Scholarship Day 2017

Dean's List at Barton College for the 2015-2018 school years

Dean's List at Craven Community College for the 2014-2015 school years

Valedictorian of High School Class

Professional Affiliations

National Society of High School Scholars

Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society